Register of the Edgardo Buscaglia and William E. Ratliff collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Edgardo Buscaglia and William E. Ratliff collection
1969-2003
97063
Hoover Institution Archives
25 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (10.4 linear feet)
The collection consists of research materials that largely relate to the study of judicial systems, legal reform, political institutions, and economic development in Latin America and internationally. The materials are chiefly comprised of official reports, laws and decrees, statistics, and printed matter dating from the late 1990s and early 2000s; there are some digital files and audiovisual materials included as well. In terms of Latin America, there is a significant amount of documentation pertaining to Argentina, Colombia, Ecuador, Paraguay, and Venezuela. The more general part of the collection contains reports and studies commissioned by the United Nations, the World Bank, and other bodies, and these focus on transnational issues of corruption, money laundering, and drug trafficking.
Buscaglia, Edgardo, collector.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1997.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
The materials in the collection were compiled by Edgardo Buscaglia and William E. Ratliff. Buscaglia is an internationally recognized expert on the judicial systems and economies of Latin America and developing countries. He was a Hoover Institution research fellow from 1991 until 2008 and is currently a Senior Research Scholar in law and economics at Columbia University. Until his death in 2014, William E. Ratliff was the Latin American curator of the Hoover Institution Archives and a Hoover Institution research fellow. He was the author of numerous works on Latin American politics.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of research materials that largely relate to the study of judicial systems, legal reform, political institutions, and economic development in Latin America and internationally. The materials are chiefly comprised of official reports, laws and decrees, statistics, and printed matter dating from the late 1990s and early 2000s. In terms of Latin America, there is a significant amount of documentation pertaining to Argentina, Colombia, Ecuador, Paraguay, and Venezuela. The more general part of the collection contains reports and studies commissioned by the United Nations, the World Bank, and other bodies, and these focus on transnational issues of corruption, money laundering, and drug trafficking.
The collection also contains some materials relating to individual countries and specific regions outside Latin America, including Africa, Singapore, and South Korea. There are also several articles by Edgardo Buscaglia in the collection, as well as a number of digital files and audiovisual recordings related to the study of Latin American judicial systems, corruption, and organized crime.
Related Collection
William E. Ratliff papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Ratliff, William E.; Laissez-faire.; Latin America--Economic conditions--1982-; Law reform--Developing countries.; Law reform--Latin America.
- Writings of Edgardo Buscaglia, 1996, 2002
  - "Sector judicial en Ecuador: Estudio descriptivo y analítico de los factores asociados a los tiempos procesales en juzgados de primera instancia,", 1996 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - With Jan van Dijk and Mark Shaw, "The TOC Convention and the Need for Comparative Research: Some Illustrations from the Work of the UN Centre for International Crime Prevention,", 2002 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Research Materials, 1969-2003
  - Latin America, 1969-2003
    - General, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Argentina, 1969-2001
      - Corruption, 1999 (Box-folder 1: 4)
      - Decrees and laws, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 1: 5-7)
      - Economy, 1987-1995 (Box-folder 1: 8-10, Box-folder 2: 1-3)
      - Education and health, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 2: 4)
      - Foreign relations, 1991 (Box-folder 2: 5)
      - Judicial system, 1969-2001 (Box-folder 2: 6-9, Box 3-5)
      - Municipal and regional government, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 6: 1-5)
      - Public opinion, 1996 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Bolivia, 1996-2003
      - Corruption, 2001 (Box-folder 6: 7)
      - Decrees and laws, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 6: 8-10)
      - Economic development, 1999 (Box-folder 6: 11)
      - Government, 1998 (Box-folder 6: 12)
      - Judicial system, 2003 (Box-folder 7: 1)
      - Money laundering, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 7: 2-3)
      - Public administration, 1996 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - Brazil, judicial system, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Chile, judicial system, 1997 (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - Colombia, 1995-2002
      - Corruption, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 7: 7-11, Box-folder 8: 1-2)
      - Judicial system, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 8: 3-10)
      - Kidnapping, 2002 (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - Municipal government, 2000 (Box-folder 9: 2)
      - Poverty, 1998 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Ecuador, 1985-2002
      - Corruption, 2002 (Box-folder 9: 4)
      - Governance, 1997 (Box-folder 9: 5)
      - Judicial system, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 9: 6-13, Box 10-11, Box-folder 12: 1-2)
        Scope and Contents note
        Box/Folder 12: 2 contains material regarding Paraguay. See also Research Materials, Paraguay, Judicial system file.
    - Guatemala, police, 2001 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - Honduras, 1996-1999
      - Government finances, 1999 (Box-folder 12: 4)
      - Judicial system, 1996, 1999 (Box-folder 12: 5-6)
    - Mexico, 1997-2003
      - Corruption, 2001 (Box-folder 12: 7)
      - Judicial system, 1997, 2000 (Box-folder 12: 8-10)
      - Kidnapping, 2003 (Box-folder 12: 11)
      - Public administration, 2001 (Box-folder 12: 12, Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Panama, judicial system, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Paraguay, 1994-1999
      - Corruption and transparency, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 13: 3)
      - Economy, 1997 (Box-folder 13: 4)
      - Government finances, 1996 (Box-folder 13: 5)
      - Judicial system, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 13: 6-10)
    - Peru, 1997, 2001
      - Corruption, 2001 (Box-folder 13: 11)
      - Judicial system, 1997 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Venezuela, 1980-2000
      - Decrees and laws, 1980, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 2-3)
      - Judicial system, 1981-2000 (Box-folder 14: 4-10, Box 15, Box-folder 16: 1-3)
      - Municipal government, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 16: 4-7, Box-folder 17: 1-4)
  - International studies and initiatives, 1992-2003
    - Corruption, 1995-2003 (Box-folder 17: 5-10, Box 18-19, Box-folder 20: 1)
    - Crime prevention and criminal justice, 1993, 1999 (Box-folder 20: 2-3)
    - Crime victims, 1999, 2002 (Box-folder 20: 4-5)
    - Crimes against humanity, 2003 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Criminal justice information systems, 2000 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - Criminology, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Drug trafficking, 1992, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 21: 2-7)
    - Foreign exchange violations, 2003 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - Governance, 2000 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - Human trafficking, 2002 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Kidnapping, 2001, 2003 (Box-folder 22: 2-4)
    - Legal reform, 2001 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Money laundering, 1998, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 22: 6-7)
    - Organized crime, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 22: 8-11, Box-folder 23: 1-3)
    - Poverty, 2002 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - Terrorism, 2002 (Box-folder 23: 5)
  - Other countries and regions, 1997-2002
    - Africa, 1997-2002
      - General, corruption, 1997, 1999, 2002 (Box-folder 23: 6-8)
      - Nigeria, 2001
        - Corruption and organized crime, 2001 (Box-folder 23: 9)
        - Judicial system, 2001 (Box-folder 24: 1)
      - South Africa, corruption, 2001 (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - Eastern Europe, corruption, 2001 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - Former Soviet Union, judicial system, 2001 (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - Hungary, corruption, 2000 (Box-folder 24: 5)
    - Serbia, judicial system, 2002 (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - Singapore, judicial system, 1991-1996, 1999 (Box-folder 24: 7-8)
    - South Korea, intellectual property, 1998 (Box-folder 24: 9)
    - Turkey, drug trafficking, 2001 (Box-folder 24: 10)
- Digital Files, 2001-2003 (Box 25)
  - "Country Assessment in Accountability and Transparency," United Nations, 2 electronic disks (CD), 1998-2001
  - Latin American and Caribbean Economic Association conference, Montevideo, Uruguay, 1 electronic disk (CD), 2001
  - "El Secuestro: Problemas sociales y jurídicos," presentation by René A. Jiménez Ornelas and Olga Islas de González Mariscal, 1 electronic disk (CD), 2002
  - "Decisiones, Tribunal Supremo de Justicia," Bolivia, 1 electronic disk (CD), 2003
  - Documents relating to corruption, governance, and organized crime in Latin America, 3 electronic disks (CD-R), 2001-2003
  - "Promoting the Ratification of the UN Convention against Transnational Organized Crime," Jakarta, Indonesia, 1 electronic disk (CD-R), 2003 February 26-28
- Audiovisual Materials, 1999-2003 (Box 25)
  - "Un día volver," Coral Corte Suprema de Justicia, Venezuela, 1 sound disc (CD), undated
  - Videorecordings, 1999-2003
    - "Las asociaciones estrategicas entre el sector público y privado," presentation by Eduardo Carabobo, San Diego, Venezuela, 1 videodisc (CD-R), 1999
    - "México contra la corrupción," 1 videodisc (CD-R), 2003
    - "Audencia publíca parroquial," 3 videocassettes (VHS), 1999
    - "El sur, un norte de esperanza," 1 videocassette (VHS), 2001
- Oversize Materials, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 26: 1-4)
  Relate to municipal government in Venezuela.